<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>iotlab &#8211; IoTLab</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 16:20:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/10/cropped-logo-1-e1666017098206-32x32.png</url>
	<title>iotlab &#8211; IoTLab</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>VBD direct contract from Pfizer-CDI</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/10/10/pfizer/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[iotlab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 17:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=15</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[VBD (Voice Based Diagnostics), direct contract from Pfizer-CDI (Center for Digital Innovation). Pfizer’s Center for Digital Innovation (CDI) in Thessaloniki is constantly investing in strategic collaborations with the Greek research and innovation ecosystem in the field of digital health technology and in this vein has announced two collaboration agreements with<a class="moretag" href="./../../../2022/10/10/pfizer/index.html"> Read more&#8230;</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>VBD (Voice Based Diagnostics), direct contract from Pfizer-CDI (Center for Digital Innovation).</p>



<p>Pfizer’s Center for Digital Innovation (CDI) in Thessaloniki is constantly investing in strategic collaborations with the Greek research and innovation ecosystem in the field of digital health technology and in this vein has announced two collaboration agreements with important Greek academic institutions: the Department of Informatics of the Aristotle University of Thessaloniki (AUTH) and the Department of Computer Engineering and Informatics of the University of Patras.</p>



<p>These are CDI’s first collaboration agreements with partners from the academic community, which expand the Center’s network of collaborations with the Greek innovation ecosystem, which has been its top priority since the start of its operation in Thessaloniki.</p>



<p>Regarding the collaboration with the Department of Computer Engineering and Informatics of the University of Patras, its aim is to develop new methods based on the Internet of Things (IoT) and Artificial Intelligence (AI) for the diagnosis of diseases based on voice.</p>



<p>Press release&nbsp;<a href="http://iotlab.ceid.upatras.gr/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/dt_cdi_synergasies_csd_ceid_18.07.20221.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU Project SynAirG</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/10/09/synairg/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[iotlab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 17:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=16</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[EU Project SynAirG (“Disrupting Noxious Synergies of Indoor Air Pollutants and their Impact in Childhood Health and Wellbeing, using Advanced Intelligent Multisensing and Green Interventions”).]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>EU Project SynAirG (“Disrupting Noxious Synergies of Indoor Air Pollutants and their Impact in Childhood Health and Wellbeing, using Advanced Intelligent Multisensing and Green Interventions”).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Prof. Sotiris Nikoletseas in the list of highly cited computer scientists</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/10/08/prof-sotiris-nikoletseas-in-the-list-of-highly-cited-computer-scientists/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[iotlab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 17:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=17</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Prof. Sotiris Nikoletseas has been included in the list of highly cited computer scientists, based on Google scholar h-index and the number of citations. http://www.guide2research.com/scientists/GR?fbclid=IwAR1kXtaRQkaoB9b2uwFLhqGJ2Dklm21F4qpTHigI3iKCI2CSmUgvk0VmeGI]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Prof. Sotiris Nikoletseas has been included in the list of highly cited computer scientists, based on Google scholar h-index and the number of citations.</p>



<p><a href="http://www.guide2research.com/scientists/GR?fbclid=IwAR1kXtaRQkaoB9b2uwFLhqGJ2Dklm21F4qpTHigI3iKCI2CSmUgvk0VmeGI" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">http://www.guide2research.com/scientists/GR?fbclid=IwAR1kXtaRQkaoB9b2uwFLhqGJ2Dklm21F4qpTHigI3iKCI2CSmUgvk0VmeGI</a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
https://www.thebest.gr/article/582118-treis-kathigites-tou-panepistimiou-patron-metaxu-ton-korufaion-epistimonon-ston-tomea-ton-ypologiston
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DCOSS 2019</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/10/07/dcoss-2019-2/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[iotlab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 17:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Prof. Sotiris Nikoletseas organizes in Greece the&#160;15th Annual International Conference on Distributed Computing in Sensor Systems. DCOSS 2019 will take place in Santorini Island, during May 29-31, 2019.&#160;In parallel to the main event it will include several thematic Workshops and Special Sessions. The event is technically supported by IEEE]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Prof. Sotiris Nikoletseas organizes in Greece the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.dcoss.org/dcoss19/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">15th Annual International Conference on Distributed Computing in Sensor Systems</a>. DCOSS 2019 will take place in Santorini Island, during May 29-31, 2019.&nbsp;In parallel to the main event it will include several thematic Workshops and Special Sessions. The event is technically supported by IEEE</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New GSRT Innovation Project “Smart Photovoltaic Plants”, 2018 – 2021</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/10/06/improve-him-believe-opinion-offered/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[iotlab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 17:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=19</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Specialized sensors and sensor networks are studied to enable wireless communication and remotely track the operation and health of photovoltaic (PV) parks.&#160;smartPV focuses on sensing temperature and humidity attributes as well as the output current and voltage. A new type of sensors will be also designed and fabricated that will<a class="moretag" href="./../../../2022/10/06/improve-him-believe-opinion-offered/index.html"> Read more&#8230;</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Specialized sensors and sensor networks are studied to enable wireless communication and remotely track the operation and health of photovoltaic (PV) parks.&nbsp;smartPV focuses on sensing temperature and humidity attributes as well as the output current and voltage. A new type of sensors will be also designed and fabricated that will better be adapted in PVs. The collected information will be analyzed with machine learning and artificial intelligence algorithms that will be able to predict future problems. One of these problems is the Potential Induced Degradation that deteriorates the performance of PVs. We will also study the possibility of incorporating the sensor networks with the future design of PV parks that may include microinverters. The participating organizations include two companies (ECOVAR and HABITATIO) and the University of Patras with three groups: SensLab (coordinator), the Laboratory of Electric Power Systems and the Department of Materials Science.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Personal Allergy Tracer</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/10/04/pat/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[iotlab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 17:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[P.A.T. (Personal Allergy Tracer) aims to create an integrated, crowdsourcing e-Health / m-Health system for the continuous monitoring of individual patient’s health status and the intelligent detection of the outbreak of their allergic illness, the frequent electronic notification of the assigned physician and finally the extraction of statistics with respect<a class="moretag" href="./../../../2022/10/04/pat/index.html"> Read more&#8230;</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>P.A.T. (Personal Allergy Tracer) aims to create an integrated, crowdsourcing e-Health / m-Health system for the continuous monitoring of individual patient’s health status and the intelligent detection of the outbreak of their allergic illness, the frequent electronic notification of the assigned physician and finally the extraction of statistics with respect to the various forms of seasonal allergies and the individuals who are<br>affected by them. The project will deliver a research prototype for the automated monitoring of patients with respiratory allergy and the development of notification services for these patients, based on kinetic and acoustic characteristics, collected from wearables and mobile devices. The crowdsourced information, collected both from sensors and other smart devices and the patient?s self-assessment, will be exploited by health professionals to better control and manage seasonal symptoms in allergic diseases in support to decision making in the allergy related medical sector.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SAFE STRIP</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/10/04/safe-strip/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[iotlab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 15:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=624</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SAFE STRIP aims to introduce a disruptive technology that will achieve to embed C-ITS applications in existing road infrastructure, including novel I2V and V2I, as well as VMS/VSL functions into low-cost, integrated strips markers on the road; to make roads self-explanatory and forgiving for all road users (trucks, cars and<a class="moretag" href="./../../../2022/10/04/safe-strip/index.html"> Read more&#8230;</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>SAFE STRIP aims to introduce a disruptive technology that will achieve to embed C-ITS applications in existing road infrastructure, including novel I2V and V2I, as well as VMS/VSL functions into low-cost, integrated strips markers on the road; to make roads self-explanatory and forgiving for all road users (trucks, cars and vulnerable road users, such as PTWs riders) and all vehicle generations (non-equipped, C-ITS equipped, autonomous), with reduced maintenance cost, full recyclability and added value services, as well as supporting real-time predictive road maintenance functions. The vast potential of SAFE STRIP will be demonstrated through applications for:</p>



<ol><li>Cooperative safety functions for enhanced ADAS/ARAS equipped and non-equipped vehicles,</li><li>Road wear level and predictive road maintenance,</li><li>Road work zones and railway crossings warnings,</li><li>Merging/intersection support,</li><li>Personalised VMS?/VDS? and Traffic Centre Information,</li><li>Dynamic trajectory estimation and interface to automated vehicles, whereas it will open a new channel to a vast array of</li><li>Supportive added value services (such as Virtual Toll Collection and Parking booking and charging).</li></ol>



<p>It will be evaluated in a test bed in Spain and in France and 2 closed test tracks in Italy and in real life conditions in Greek and Italian highways, with 4 car and 3 PTW demonstrators.</p>



<p>This very challenging task is undertaken by a muldisciplinary and complementary Consortium of 18 Partners from 6 countries, with a good representation of all stakeholders: 1 vehicle OEM (CRF), 1 PTW OEM (Piaggio), 2 system integrators and infrastructure installers (3M &amp; CEA), 2 Tier 1 suppliers (CONTI &amp; VALEO), 1 SME (RELAB), 8 R&amp;D Institutes (CERTH, UNITN, UPAT, FhG/IAO, CNR, CIDAUT, CTI and ICCS) and 2 end users (ATTD and ?22) as beneficiaries, under the umbrella of ERTICO; thus providing further access to all key stakeholders in the area.</p>



<p><a href="http://safestrip.eu/">http://safestrip.eu/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
